<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-06-06T13:32:44+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">garybuckle</title><subtitle>Health, fitness, running, squash, boxing, diet.... being something or someone that makes you happy!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Online Training Websites</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/injuries/2018/05/26/online-training-websites.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Online Training Websites" /><published>2018-05-26T11:31:50+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T11:31:50+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/injuries/2018/05/26/online%20training%20websites</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/injuries/2018/05/26/online-training-websites.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;using-online-logging-tools-to-guide-your-training&quot;&gt;Using Online logging tools to guide your training&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very basic entry about how logging your fitness sessions can be useful as a motivational tool, sounds very obvious now that I’m writing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of them about and I’ve used a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As already stated, there are many options available, some free and some that you have to subscribe to.
The two big sports/fitness manufacturers Garmin and Polar both have very good online facilities and apps for capturing and displaying the data.
Other online portals or tools like &lt;a href=&quot;www.trainingpeaks.com&quot;&gt;Training Peaks&lt;/a&gt; are not free but very useful and comprehensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-log-your-exercises&quot;&gt;Why log your exercises?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you start you will have done idea of where you want to get to and you will know where you are. You will continually strive to get to where you want to be but will easily forget where you started.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having a visual reminder of your efforts may inspire you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You may become obsessed with logging the workout.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can workout effectively and not waste your valuable time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Others will see your efforts and comment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, again I can only offer my experience and my data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My experience was that logging my workouts initially highlighted how poor my performance was when compared to what it was years ago. Rather than dishearten me though it gave me a ground zero starting point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting at the bottom gave me a  “I can only get better” approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I progressed the progression that I could clearly see was inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friends and family who commented on my workouts were encouraging and positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I became very fit, I was able to take rest days in order to prevent burn out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became obsessed with logging, it made me get out of bed in the mornings when I envisaged hitting my target of 10 hours of Squash in a given week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence my reward system was sufficiently triggered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I installed positive habits in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the record I used Garmin and Polar flow, decisions driven by the use of equipment like gps watches and fitness trackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously I’d also used &lt;a href=&quot;www.runkeeper.com&quot;&gt;Runkeeper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently I use &lt;a href=&quot;www.&quot;&gt;Polar Flow&lt;/a&gt; and have the account linked to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/&quot;&gt;Strava&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m focusing on Polar because all of the features it offers are essentially free, _
As long as you have a Polar device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does the Polar Flow service do for me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heart Rate- Min, Max and zones.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially there isn’t a lot of data to go on so the site or mobile app might look a bit barren.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more you exercise, the more gets displayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of a Squash session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/polar/Polar HR Example.png&quot; alt=&quot;HR Data&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is currently being developed, I will add more in due course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to comment on this post then please &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:iambuckle@mac.com&quot;&gt;mail me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Using Online logging tools to guide your training</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Detached Retina!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/injuries/2018/05/24/Detatched-Retina-recovery-for-Athletes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Detached Retina!" /><published>2018-05-24T23:31:50+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-24T23:31:50+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/injuries/2018/05/24/Detatched%20Retina%20recovery%20for%20Athletes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/injuries/2018/05/24/Detatched-Retina-recovery-for-Athletes.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;recovering-from-a-detached-retina&quot;&gt;recovering from a detached retina.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nhs.uk/conditions/detached-retina-retinal-detachment/&quot;&gt;what is a detached retina&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone active in sports activities this is quite a traumatic experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was certainly the case for me, coming in a period where I was getting ready for a marathon, challenging in local squash leagues and enjoying a high level of fitness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can think of no particular reason why this happened. No squash ball in the eye, no one punched me and I certainly had no trauma that I can recollect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first recollection of anything untoward was having floaters, actually in both eyes.
The diagnosis from  My first hospital visit was a retinal tear, he treatment for which is laser treatment and fairly standard.
Performed on the same day as my appointment, unfortunately it didn’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This meant I was sent to another hospital for a deeper, more intensive operation to fix the tear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was there that I was informed I had a detached retina.
Initially it’s a bit of a shock since I’d no idea what that actually meant.
In any case the operation consists of laser treatment to ‘weld’ the retina back on to the wall of the eye.
In order to make the operation a success two things happen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A gas bubble is inserted into the liquid (vitreous) of the eye.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;for 5 days after the operation I had to posture. For 50 minutes of every 60 I had to lie with my head horizontal on the right hand side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not easy but I did it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One complication I should mention, since if you’ve stayed awake so far  you might as well know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After two days I was experiencing pain in my left eye along with headaches, nausea and sickness.
I returned to hospital where after measuring my ocular pressure was told that it was dangerously high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So they operated again and removed some of the gas out of the bubble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All was well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continued my recovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost two weeks post op, I was told by the surgeon that all looked good and I could resume light exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gas bubble would slowly dissipate and my world would return to pre op status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So on Wednesday March the 28th with 6 weeks before my next marathon in Copenhagen I decided to resume light training.
I wasn’t at all sure what that meant or what I wanted to do.
I knew I had to do something!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was our wedding anniversary and my wife and I were going to have a meal together. I was feeling very good, I wanted to do something that made me feel even better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, drawing from 40 years of experience I did the thing that linked back to my youth.
Skipping!
20 minutes of jumping rope.
A classic warm up routine back in the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donning my eye patch safety glasses to avoid the gas bubble from making me nauseous I started the routine.
Headphones on, Reggae and Cumbia washing over me.
Patterns and movements I’d honed over the years feeding my soul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep it felt great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the session I made my way back into my house and felt the sweat coving my body.
I was back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Removing the glasses I was greeted with a black screen on my left eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like black sky!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out my eye had haemorrhaged.
The iris flooded with blood, I was blind in my left eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After calls and visits to the hospital it transpired that not only had the eye haemorrhaged but that the retina had also detached once more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday the 7th of April I was operated on for a second time.
The result of which was more laser and the insertion of silicon oil in the eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially the prognosis was very grim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“This might not be the last time we need to operate”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“We cannot guarantee that your retina will not detach again”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Your vision in the left eye may not return to anything like it was previously “&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“You may discover that your running days are over”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not inspiring stuff!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was actually not disheartened by the candid outlook dispensed by the surgeon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two weeks later though his diagnosis was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Actually, it’s not bad!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was encouraged by the results.
Despite the blurry vision, a result of dilating eye drops and the Silicon Oil.
I could see through the portal of my left socket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So from the 7th of April till the 28th I did nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No walks, no runs, no squash just nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20 days is not long but it was a lifetime to me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add to that the prospect of face down posturing for 50 minutes of every hour for the first 7 days post op.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 28th of April I ventured out.
Advice from the surgeon had been to wait until the eye drops were finished and start walking. His advice was to do sports that did not involve rapid movement of the head or heavy vibration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Walking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cycling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perfect!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 3 weeks I started walking and 5 weeks post op, on the 14th of May I started cycling.
On the 25th of May I did 5k on a concept 2 Ergo rowing machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a recipe, a game plan that touch wood has so far appeared to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will update the post as I progress but as always please consider that all medical conditions are personal and never do anything unless you’ve checked it out with the medical staff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to comment on this post then please &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:iambuckle@mac.com&quot;&gt;mail me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current time stamp is Thursday 2018-05-31 09:52:05a&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">recovering from a detached retina. what is a detached retina.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fixing Polar V800 Pairing issue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/equipment/2018/05/16/Polar-V800-Pairing-discovery.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fixing Polar V800 Pairing issue" /><published>2018-05-16T11:31:50+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-16T11:31:50+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/equipment/2018/05/16/Polar%20V800%20Pairing%20discovery</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/equipment/2018/05/16/Polar-V800-Pairing-discovery.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-polar-refuses-to-pair-with-polar--flow-on-ios-device&quot;&gt;New Polar refuses to pair with Polar  Flow on iOS device&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;error message is ‘pairing failed’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-context-around-the-issue&quot;&gt;Some context around the issue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently purchased another Polar device (second Hand). I already own a M400 but the second hand one was a three year old V800 with a gorgeous blue triathlon strap .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I couldnt resist buying it!!!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When pairing the new device for the first time it was fine.
I had to unpair it because I had it tested by Polar (for free). So in order to (re) pair my old M400 I had to unpair te V800. On receiving the V800 back from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.polar.com/uk-en&quot;&gt;Polar&lt;/a&gt; I had issues pairing with the polar flow app on my iOS device.
Removing it from the account, deleting and reinstalling the Polar Flow app and repairing it from the watch resulted in the pairing error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-fix&quot;&gt;The Fix.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure that you remove the Bluetooth v800 entry under the Bluetooth menu on iOS. 
Otherwise although the device appears to pair, it actually does not pair and will say pairing failed even after entry of the pin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to comment on this post then please &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:iambuckle@mac.com&quot;&gt;mail me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">New Polar refuses to pair with Polar Flow on iOS device error message is ‘pairing failed’</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recovering from Injuries</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/injuries/2018/05/11/recovery.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recovering from Injuries" /><published>2018-05-11T10:31:50+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-11T10:31:50+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/injuries/2018/05/11/recovery</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/injuries/2018/05/11/recovery.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;recovering-from-an-injury&quot;&gt;Recovering from an injury.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Types of Injury&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Muscular&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skeletal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Recovering from an injury.</summary></entry></feed>